I look at beauty, all these beautiful indigenous peoples across the world and the ways in which
their cultures and their lands have been attempted to be stolen and taken and successfully been
stolen and taken, et cetera. And then I think about us Black Americans and how so many of us
don't understand that we are special. And something that is so uniquely special to us
that we see all the time is our innovation, our ability to create. And I don't think folks
understand that we've had to create our culture. We are a new people. Do you know that?
We are a version of indigeneity that to my knowledge, the world has never seen before.
We have had to form our indigeneity within us because we weren't given the option or the
opportunity to form it in the land. We had to be the land. We have had to be the soil. It has grown
directly from us. And so that is why there is so much effort to keep us separated because were we
to actually come together. Imagine how we would be able to shift things because we would be a whole
other land on this land. I wish we all knew how special we were and how even more effective we
would be were we special together.